<p>When I fast time played video games in my Personal Computer.
Sometimes, I had impress by the storyline that describe in the games.
The way the game creators combine the story of myth or historical events
into their game, always makes me want to dig out the stories further.
For example, the use of the story about god Balder. In the famous video
game, God of War lV.</p>
<figure>
  <head>Balder hurts by <hi rend="italic">mistletoe</hi> arrow</head>
  <graphic url="https://i.redd.it/fanvqw498lk51.jpg" />
  <figDesc>fig: a clip from God of War IV</figDesc>
</figure>
<div type="level1" xml:id="balder-and-mistletoe-and-loki">
  <head>Balder and <hi rend="italic"><hi rend="italic">mistletoe</hi></hi> and Loki</head>
  <p><hi rendition="simple:bold">The Death of Balder In God of War
  IV</hi></p>
  <p>
  <lb/>In the game God of War IV, the story of Kratos has moved from Greek
  <lb/>Mythology to Norse Mythology. In the new storyline, the adventure was no
  <lb/>longer about the revenge to Greek God, but the adventure of him and
  <lb/>his son-Atreus. At the end of the game, we know his really name was
  <lb/>Loki. Balder, the son of <hi rend="italic">Frigg</hi>(Freya) as the main antagonist made most
  <lb/>of the trouble to Kratos and Loki. Like what had been told in legend,
  <lb/>Balder is invincible. no one can hurt him, but a tiny plant-<hi rend="italic"><hi rend="italic">mistletoe</hi></hi>.
  <lb/>In the original myth, Hodur(Höðr), the brother of Balder, killed
  <lb/>Balder with <hi rend="italic"><hi rend="italic">mistletoe</hi></hi>, which was given by Loki. However, in God of War
  <lb/>IV, Balder was killed by Loki with <hi rend="italic">mistletoe</hi> arrow.
  </p>
  <p><hi rendition="simple:bold">more detail from game clips:</hi>
  https://youtu.be/15SoKi1z_JI</p>
</div>
<div type="level1" xml:id="the-death-of-balder-in-golden-bough">
  <head>The Death of Balder In Golden Bough</head>
  <TEI>
    <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
        <titleStmt>
          <title>The Golden Bough: A Stuudy in Comparative Religion</title>
        </titleStmt>
        <publicationStmt>
          <p>Macmillan. Ltd (1st edition)</p>
        </publicationStmt>
        <sourceDesc>
          <p>Wikisource</p>
          <p>also Gutenberg Project</p>
        </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <div type ="chapter">
    <author><hi rend="small-capitals">James Frazer</hi></author>
    <p>[Chapter 61]</p>
    <p><quote>Once upon a time <name><hi rend="italic">Balder</hi></name> dreamed heavy dreams which seemed
    to forbode his death. Thereupon the gods held a council and resolved
    to make Balder secure against every danger. So the goddess <hi rend="italic">Frigg</hi>
    took an oath from fire and water, iron and all metals, stones and
    earth, from trees, sicknesses and poisons, and from all four-footed
    beasts, birds and creeping things, that they would not hurt Balder.
    When this was done <name><hi rend="italic">Balder</hi></name> was deemed invulnerable; so the gods
    amused themselves by setting him in their midst, while some shot at
    him, others hewed at him, and others threw stones at him. But
    whatever they did, nothing could hurt him; and at this they were all
    glad.</quote></p>
    <p><quote>Only <name><hi rend="italic">Loki</hi></name>, the mischief maker, was displeased, and he went
    in the guise of an old women to <hi rend="italic">Frigg</hi>, who told him that the weapons
    of the gods could not hurt Balder, since she had made them all swear
    not to hurt him. Then Loki asked, <quote>have all things sworn to
    spare Balder?</quote> She answered, <quote>East of Valhalla grows a
    plant called <hi rend="italic">mistletoe</hi>; it seemed to me too young to swear</quote>.
    So Loki went and pulled the <hi rend="italic">mistletoe</hi> and took it to the assembly of
    the gods. There he found the blind god <hi rend="italic">Hother</hi> standing at the
    outside of the circle. Loki asked him, <said>Why do you not shoot
    at Balder?</said><name><hi rend="italic">Hother</hi></name> answered, <said>Because I do not see
    where he stands; besides I have no weapon.</said> Then said Loki,
    <said>Do like the rest and show Balder honour, as they all do. I
    will show you where he stands, and do you shoot at him with this
    twig.</said> <name><hi rend="italic">Hother</hi></name> took the <hi rend="italic">mistletoe</hi> and threw it at Balder, as
    <name><hi rend="italic">Loki</hi></name> directed him. The <hi rend="italic">mistletoe</hi> struck Balder and pierced him
    through and through, and he fell down dead. For a while the gods
    stood speechless, then they lifted up their voices and wept
    bitterly.</quote></p>
    <p><hi rendition="simple:italic">Source:</hi><lb />https://en.wikisource.org/wiki/The_Golden_Bough/The_Myth_of_Balder</p>
  </div>
</div>
